Dad. Mom.
爸爸 妈妈
I am Kazuma.
我是和真
I defeated the leaders of the Devil King's Army who were a threat to the world…
威胁这个世界的魔王军干部们…
Oh my.
哎呀
This was mentioned in the previous letter.
这在之前的信里提过
Sorry.
不好意思
Exactly, exactly.
没错没错
The world's women are enamored
因为我如此杰出
with me and say they want to have my children
世上的女性都对我投以热情的目光
because I am so great.
说想怀上和真先生的孩子
Attractive women also passionately
身材火辣的大姐姐们
seduce me.
也热情地诱惑我
I might be able to show you
我也许很快就能让你们
your grandson soon.
看到孙子的脸了
Oh, it's Mr. Kazuma who defeated leaders of Devil King's Army again.
又打倒魔王军干部的和真先生
Mr. Kazuma, the future hero candidate.
未来的勇者候补和真先生
Mr. Kazuma, the tycoon.
大富翁和真先生
Marry me.
娶我吧
-Calm down. -So cunning.
-冷静点 -好奸诈
-Because there's only one of me. -I want to marry him, too!
-因为我只有一个 -我也要 我也要
Alright, alright.
好啦好啦
Oh, my.
哎呀
They're so anxious.
真心急呢
Calm down.
冷静点
Hey, don't do that here.
喂喂 别在这种地方乱来
Wait, you're really rude.
等等 真粗鲁
Hey, stop it!
喂 住手
I am a conservative and reserved man
我是重视按部就班
who prefers to take things slowly!
保守又内敛的男人耶
I got you.
碰到了啊
I like…
喜欢…
I quite like…
超…喜欢
I got you.
碰到了啊
(Episode 1: A Toast to a Bright Future)
(第1集 为光明的未来干杯)
Megumin, Megumin.
惠惠 惠惠
What is it?
什么事
Did you see the souvenirs I bought in the Crimson Demon Village?
你知道从红魔之里 买回来的土产在哪吗
If you mean the bubble wine, it's empty.
泡泡酒的话已经空了
So I put it away.
所以我收掉了
That's strange.
太奇怪了
Hey, Kazuma.
喂 和真
You didn't drink my bubble wine, did you?
你该不会把我的泡泡酒喝掉了吧
Are you listening, Kazuma?
你有在听吗 和真
My bubble wine…
我的泡泡酒…
The wind…
风…
What?
什么
The sun…
太阳…
What's wrong with him?
他怎么了
This is completely out of character for him to do.
居然做这种不符合他风格的事
It is difficult not to appreciate these things,
和真也是花样年华的男生
especially since Kazuma is also a young man in the prime of his life.
难免会对这些事物发出感叹
I understand it very well.
我了解 我非常了解
Mr. Kazuma?
和…和真先生?
If you scream all of a sudden, you might scare us.
你突然大叫会害我们吓到的
Forget about the bubble wine.
泡…泡泡酒的事就算了
What are you talking about?
你在说什么
You arrived so early.
你们怎么这么早就来了
We've received the reward for saving the Crimson Demon Village.
我们拿到拯救红魔之里的奖金了
Bring over some more bubble wine.
再多拿一些泡泡酒过来
Hey, you're too impatient. Useless Goddess.
喂喂 你太性急了 废物女神
You should pay for it first before…
这种事应该先付过钱再…
Lady, another glass of bubble wine, please!
小姐 再来一杯泡泡酒
Me too!
大姐姐 我也要一杯泡泡酒
No, Megumin, you can't drink yet.
不 惠惠还不能喝啦
So cunning! I also want to drink bubble wine.
好狡猾 我也想喝泡泡酒
No, you can't drink this.
不行不行 小妹妹不能喝
You've been starting to drink at noon.
从中午就吃这么好
Let me join…
也请我吃…
Don't stand behind me!
不要站在我后面
The wind…
风…
I want to become a monk.
我想出家
What?
什么
What's wrong with you?
你…你是怎么了啊
You want to be a monk and shave your head, right?
你要当和尚是吧 剃光头
It has nothing to do with shaving my head.
跟剃光头没关系
Mr. Kazuma.
和真先生 和真先生
If you really want to become a monk,
既然要出家
I think you should join the Axis Order.
我强力推荐你加入阿克西斯教
You're so annoying.
烦死了
No matter what, that is the one place I would never set foot in.
只有那里我死都不会去
Tell us the reason. What happened to you?
告诉我们原因吧 是什么原因
I once believed
我曾经想过
spring will come.
这个世界的春天会来临
Yunyun said she wanted to have my child.
听到芸芸说想怀我的孩子
And I shared a bed with that girl over there.
还跟那边的小妹妹同床共枕
Those made me think that I will be in love.
兴奋地以为自己桃花运来了
Yet, I'm still single now.
结果现在还是单身
Being attacked by orcs, going through a crisis
要说有什么收获
of the virginity, and suffering from a mental disorder brought
只有被半兽人袭击 陷入贞操危机
by a love suicide with Chimera are all I can say as my accomplishments.
还有和奇美拉殉情 所引发的精神错乱
I misunderstood.
我…误会了
You must be tired.
你累了吧
I'd like to say this to you.
我想对这样的你说这句话
The doctrine of the Axis Order.
阿克西斯教教义
You…
你…
Stop it!
别说了
I ended up like this by doing exactly as I was told.
我就是照着做才会变成这样
I won't make the same mistake again.
我不会再重蹈覆辙了
Hmph.
哼
I want to become a monk, instead of an adventurer.
我要从冒险者转行当和尚
Don't get in my way.
别妨碍我
Is there a graduation for those who are brave but reckless?
有勇无谋的毕业吗
But this is good sometimes.
但有时候这样也好
Especially for young people.
特别是年轻人
Because you possess endless possibilities.
因为你们拥有无穷的可能性
Thank you.
谢谢
Lady, introduce me to a temple, please.
小姐 帮我介绍寺庙
What sect do you wish to join?
你想加入什么宗派
I want to join a more strict sect.
我想加入严格一点的宗派
Okay.
好
How about this one?
这个怎么样
Although it's a bit far.
虽然有点远
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you for your help.
承蒙你的关照了
On top of that, I used to like you!
另外 我曾经喜欢过你
Kazuma!
和真
Wait a minute.
等一下
Kazuma, think about it again.
你重新考虑一下啦 和真
Yeah, think about it again.
就是说啊
You should first take a nap…
这时候应该先睡一觉再…
Don't worry.
别担心啦
He will start
到了下午
to miss the bubble wine by the afternoon anyway.
他一定就会开始想念泡泡酒了
Cut the chatter.
少啰嗦
Don't compare me with you, Useless Goddess.
别把我跟你相提并论 废物女神
You're calling me Useless Goddess again!
你又骂我是废物女神
What's wrong with calling you Useless Goddess…
骂废物女神是废物女神有什么…
Goodbye.
再见了
Explosion!
爆裂魔法
What's this?
这是…
My determination is more steadfast than that rocky mountain.
我的决心比那座石头山还坚定
Pfft.
噗噗噗噗
Kazuma, you are fragile,
内心比豆腐还脆弱的和真这么说
so this does not make any sense at all.
根本没有说服力
Hey, you!
喂 你这家伙
Alright, clench your teeth.
好啊 你给我咬紧牙关
I'll teach you a lesson right now with my gender-equal punch.
我现在就用男女平等拳教训你
Calm down, Kazuma.
冷静点 和真
You have gone too far, Aqua.
阿库娅也是 你笑过头了
Pfft.
噗噗噗噗
What are you doing? You're so childish.
搞什么啊 真幼稚
You should stay even more calm in these situations.
这种时候更应该保持冷静
What is with the grown-up act
你装什么成熟啊
when you are obviously just a little girl?
明明是个小妹妹
Your flat body
到底什么时候才会长大啊
never changes.
你那平板的身体曲线
You're making me mad.
真火大
If you rile a tiger, it's going to show its claws.
老虎不发威 你就当我是病猫
Okay then.
好啊
Let me demolish your insignificant determination.
就让我来击碎 你微不足道的决心吧
It must be that mountain.
是那座山吧
Explosion!
爆裂魔法
We have not camped outside like this in a while.
我们好久没像这样露宿野外了
Are you kidding yourself?
你少在那边自欺欺人了
Tomorrow, you should leave on your own.
明天给我自己走
I was supposed to arrive today.
我本来预定今天要到的
I got you.
碰到了啊
Kazuma, are you okay?
和真 你真的没关系吗
You have clairvoyance and the ability to sense enemies,
拥有千里眼 和感应敌人能力的你醒着
so being awake is beneficial to us, but…
对我们来说是好事 不过…
Don't worry about that.
别在意
I often stay up late in my country, too.
我在我的国家也常常熬夜
So you're actually good at staying up late.
竟然擅长熬夜
What was your life like before?
你之前都过着怎样的生活啊
Well.
这个嘛
Attacking fortresses with comrades
和战友一起进攻要塞
and hunting formidable Demon Lord.
狩猎厉害的大魔王
I did many strange things when I was not sleeping.
我不睡觉做了很多乱来的事
Th-That's amazing.
好…好厉害
He doesn't seem to be lying.
他感觉不像在说谎
Kazuma's current expression
从和真现在的表情
does show both confidence and longing.
的确能看出自信和怀念
You're talking about an online game, right?
你说的是在线游戏吧
(Konosuba) Shh.
嘘
A little roughness is acceptable
如果发生什么事
in the event of an emergency.
粗暴一点也没关系
Just wake me up.
拜托你叫醒我
Got it.
知道了
I'll wake you up in a surprising way.
我会用惊奇的方式叫醒你
I just remind you.
我提醒你
Don't cross the line with a friend.
不能跨越伙伴的底线哦
Men are creatures of challenge.
男人这种生物啊
the more you tell them a wall is unclimbable,
你越叫他不能翻过哪道墙
the more they are compelled to try.
他就越想翻过去
Why do you say those things with a carefree look?
你干嘛一脸潇洒说这种话
Another glass of bubble wine, please!
再来一杯泡泡酒
Hey,
我问你
why haven't you gone back to your country?
你没有回过国吗
I am unable to return, even though I wish to do so.
就算我想回去也回不去啊
If your parents found out all of a sudden
要是你的父母
that you were going to become a monk…
突然听说你要出家的话…
That is maddening.
烦死了
We are done with this topic.
这个话题已经结束…
Kazuma, it was you
是和真
who let me keep going down the path of Explosion Magic.
让我继续走爆裂魔法这条路
You have only seen the 120-point Explosion Magic, right?
你只看过120分的爆裂魔法吧
I will show you
总有一天
the 200-point Explosion Magic one day.
我会让你看看 满分200分的爆裂魔法
W-Well.
这…这个嘛
It is also not bad to live with everyone.
跟大家一起生活也不错
Probably.
大概吧
Saving the Crimson Demon Village also earns us a reward.
还拿到拯救红魔之里的奖金
Y-You have a point.
说…说得也是
I doubt that becoming
就算成为和尚
a monk would bring me inner peace.
内心也不见得能得到平静
Wait a minute.
等一下
Vanir and I still need to talk about business.
我还要跟巴尼尔谈生意
We are surely able to make a lot of money.
应该能得到一大笔钱
A fun and relaxing life together
大家一起过着好玩又悠闲的生活
seems like a good idea.
好像也不错
I also like my current life a lot,
我也很喜欢现在的生活
so I want to keep things the same.
所以想维持现状
No matter how many crises we encounter,
不管是动不动就遇到危机
we always manage to find a way to overcome them by working together.
还是跟大家一起想办法化解
What is the fun in living a life
不 动不动就遇到危机的生活
full of crises all the time?
哪里好玩了啊
It…
要是…
It would be great if we could ever stay together like this.
要是大家能像这样 永远在一起就好了
Oh no!
讨厌
What is this touching scene?
这是什么酸酸甜甜的场景
What should I do? what is she doing?
怎么办 她在干嘛
Why is she holding my hand all of a sudden?
为什么要突然握我的手
Will I be in love?
我的桃花运果然来了吗
Is she seducing me?
她在诱惑我吗
In this case, would not it be better to just say something nice?
现在只要说句动听的话就好?
What could I possibly say?
我哪说得出来啊
Do not think too little of pure boy.
别小看纯情男孩
Calm down and take a deep breath first.
冷静点 先深呼吸
Okay.
好
Megumin,
惠惠 我…
I have changed my mind about becoming a monk.
还是决定不出家…
(Konosuba) Gosh.
天啊
Near the end of this forest?
在这片森林的尽头吗
My second chapter is about to begin?
我的第二章要开始了啊
-You will undoubtedly return in tears. -I-I've been treated unfairly.
-我…我被做了过分的事 -反正你一定会哭着回来
I will have a cold glass of bubble wine ready for you.
我会准备冰凉的泡泡酒等你的
Shut up!
烦死了
Megumin, what's the matter?
惠惠 是什么事
What exactly happened to you?
你到底遇到了什么事
It seems like someone is there.
好像有人在
She's hurt.
她受伤了耶
Are you okay?
你没事吧
That is a mimic monster.
那个…是拟态的怪物
Huh?
咦
My enemy detection skill sends out an alarm.
感应敌人技能正在发出警讯
Hey, Kazuma.
喂 和真
-What's wrong? -I don't know why
-我是和真 -不知道为什么
I have a strong desire to help her heal.
我好想帮她疗伤哦
Easygoing girl, a plant-type monster.
安乐少女 植物型怪物
It is a scary monster that makes people who pass by
会让路过的旅人产生强烈保护欲
have a strong desire to protect it.
是危险的怪物
Hey, Kazuma.
喂 和真
-What's wrong? -I don't know why
-我是和真 -不知道为什么
she looked at me so sadly.
她好像露出快哭的表情看着我
As long as you stay with her,
只要待在她身边
she will smile in a way that makes you feel
她就会露出非常安心的笑容
so good that you cannot leave her.
让人无论如何都离不开她
It is more likely that this monster will capture travelers who are kind.
越善良的旅人 越容易被这个怪物俘虏
Be more careful.
千万要小心
-Ka-Kazuma. -It hurts.
-和…和真 -好痛
-She is really trying hard not to cry out loud. -What's wrong?
-她拼命忍住不哭出来 -我是和真
Can I hold her for a bit?
我能不能稍微抱抱她呢
Are you all listening to me?
你们有在听我说话吗
The guild has designated her as a priority expulsion monster.
她可是公会指定的重点驱逐怪物耶
I will heal you right now.
我现在就帮你治疗
It is already fine.
已经没事了
Strange, this isn't a bandage.
奇怪 这不是绷带
But it looks like bandage mimicry.
而是看起来像绷带的拟态
According to the book, she arouses the travelers' protective desire
她就是利用这种保护欲绊住旅人
to ensnare them,
让他们饿死
causing them to starve to death and taking root in their bodies.
在他们身上扎根
Wait. What are you going to do, Kazuma?
等一下 你想做什么 和真
I won't let you do that.
我不会让你这么做
I don't want to do this either.
我也不想做这种事
I have no choice.
有什么办法
Are you going to kill me?
你要杀我吗
She can talk?
她会讲话啊
Are you even looking at me in this way?
不要连你都用这种眼神看我
Rest assured.
放心吧
I am going to make this man shut up
我会用神圣的铁拳
with the holy iron fist.
让这个男人闭嘴的
Are you going to kill me?
你要杀我吗
Get yourself together. She is going to kill people.
振作点 她会夺走人命耶
It is bad to leave her alone?
放着她不管才是坏事吧
Or it is bad to to get rid of her?
还是说 除掉她才是坏事呢
Kazuma.
和真
You will regret it
迷惘的时候做出的决定
when making a choice amidst confusion.
不管怎样一定会后悔的
That being the case,
既然这样
pick the easier side now.
现在就选择轻松的那边吧
This is such a careless idea.
真不负责任的建议
Is not this how a useless person thinks?
这不是废物的思考方式吗
I'm sorry. It's all because I exist in this world.
对不起 都是我活着不好
Because I am a monster.
因为我是怪物
So…
所以
As long as I live, I will make trouble for others.
只要活着就会给人添麻烦
This is the first time I have ever talked to a human.
这是我有生以来第一次和人类交谈
What a great thing that you can be
第一个和最后一个见到的人
the first and last person I see.
是你真的太好了
I hope that if I had a second chance at life,
假如能投胎转世
I would not be a monster.
我希望下辈子不要当怪物
It was so hard for me to do it.
这样我哪下得了手啊
Damn it.
可恶
It feels bad
不管放过那只怪物
whether I spare that monster
还是杀死那只怪物
or kill it.
感觉都很差
It looks like you still have your humanity.
看来你还保有人心嘛
Of course.
那当然啦
She said
不过
this was her first time she's talking to a person.
她说这次她第一次和人类交谈
So it is likely that she has not killed anyone yet.
那她应该还没杀过任何人吧
Strange.
奇怪
Wait a minute.
等一下
What's wrong?
怎么了
Do you have a stomachache?
你肚子痛吗
I had tissue with me.
我有带卫生纸哦
No, it's not that.
不是啦
I suddenly thought of something.
我只是突然想起一件事
I'll be right back.
我马上就回来
Pfft.
噗噗噗噗
He gets embarrassed very easily.
真容易害羞
(Konosuba) Shut up!
吵死了
This is the path to the temple.
这是通往寺庙的参道
I'll go tell her
去拜托她
not to wave at passersby under any circumstances.
就算看到有人经过也别招手吧
That's right.
对了
If I can get her to agree,
如果能说服她
I will send her food
我就每天从寺庙
from the temple every day.
送能当养分的东西给她也不错
Right, right.
没错没错
My decision to become a monk may be destined.
我决定出家这件事也许是命运
Yes, it must be so.
没错 一定是这样
Hey.
喂…
Those guys just now have good physiques.
刚刚那些家伙体格不错
They seem like they could be good nourishment.
似乎能成为很好的养分
But it still feels like something is missing.
但总觉得美中不足
Are you going to kill me?
你要杀我…吗
If…
假如…
I hope that if I had a second chance at life…
假如能投胎转世
Humans…
人类…
Family…
家人…
Friends…
朋友…
Friends!
朋友
This is good.
这个不错
There is no doubt that it will move people.
一定能触动人心
I hope that if I had a second chance at life…
假如能投胎转世
I hope
我希望下辈子
we can be friends.
能和你当朋友
Hilarious.
超好笑
This is just perfect.
这个太完美了
The nutrients in this guy are almost gone.
这家伙的养分也快见底了
When foods show up again,
下次诱饵出现的时候
I will use this strong statement
就用这句强而有力的话
to kill them right away.
一击杀了他们吧
Great! The sky is very clear.
好耶 天气也很晴朗
Let's do photosynthesis.
来行光合作用吧
Friends…
朋友…
Disregard what I just said.
刚刚那些话当我没说
Do not you remember how well you spoke just now?
你刚刚讲话不是很流畅吗
Idiot.
蠢货
(Konosuba) Friends!
朋友
Let's go back.
回去吧
What?
什么
All of a sudden, I can see many things through.
我突然看清很多事
Let's go back to Axel.
我们回阿克塞尔吧
Really? Kazuma.
真的吗 和真
Yeah.
嗯
You look like you're having a good time.
你看起来一脸畅快呢
You must have been pooping a lot, right?
应该拉了很多东西吧
Yeah.
嗯
Is there no need for toilet paper?
没有卫生纸没关系吗
Huh?
嗯?
I told you that it was not that.
都说了不是那样
Strange.
奇怪
Where did this hammer come from?
这个小槌子是哪来的
After discovering a dead body, I went to bury him
我刚才发现死人 去把他埋起来
and discovered this hammer.
是那时候捡到的
I feel like I've seen this somewhere.
我好像在哪里见过
Let me take a look.
借我看看
Hey, stop it.
喂 住手
-Don't treat it roughly. -Just for a second.
-一下下就好 -别粗鲁对待它
-This thing might be valuable.
-这东西也许很值钱
(Konosuba) Let's go back.
回去吧
I got you.
碰到了啊
Got you.
碰到…
I got you!
碰到了啊
Hey, you there!
喂 你这家伙
Mr. Kazuma.
和真先生 和真先生
I have been dying to try a certain brand of high-end bubble wine.
我一直想喝某牌的高级泡泡酒
I'll buy it for you.
我买给你 我买给你
Oh, as long as one has money,
哎呀 人只要有钱
the mental state will be different.
心境就会不一样
Hey!
喂
Chris.
克莉丝
Hey.
嗨
It seems like today is a very pleasant day for you all.
你们今天的心情格外地好呢
We are now going to celebrate Kazuma's comeback.
我们现在要去庆祝和真复出
-Comeback? -Do you want to join us?
-复出? -你要不要一起来
Come join us.
一起来吧
Don't worry about money.
不用在意钱
Sorry, I happen to have plans today.
抱歉 我今天刚好有事
Let's make it another time.
下次再约吧
Okay, no problem.
好 没问题
Goodbye.
再见
Kazuma, Kazuma.
和真 和真
I also want to have a robe.
我也有一件想要的长袍
I'll buy it for you.
我买给你 我买给你
I'll use the Wish Granting Hammer right now…
我现在就用愿望槌…
(Konosuba) My hammer!
小槌子
I am never going to leave this house again.
我不会再踏出这栋房子
It's wrong for a homebody like me
像我这种家里蹲想做些什么
to try to do something.
本身就是错的
It is too bad about the hammer,
虽然小槌子很可惜
but it is great that you could return to your original self.
但和真能恢复原样真是太好了
I can't stand you.
真受不了你
You started to slack off all at once.
一下子就开始摆烂了
But for some reason, it's truly reassuring.
但不知道为什么 真令人放心
I feel like I do not have to try so hard anymore either.
感觉这样子我也不用努力了
Aqua, you can't slack off either.
阿库娅不能也跟着堕落
Excuse me.
不好意思
Is anyone there?
请问有人在吗
Is anyone…
请问有人…
Take this!
看招
What's going on?
你们想做什么
S-Stop it!
住…住手
I am not sure who you are,
我不知道你是什么来头
but you must be causing some sort of trouble.
反正一定是什么麻烦事
Go back, you god of plague.
给我回去 你这个瘟神
Kazuma, use Drain Touch.
和真 用Drain Touch
Use Drain Touch to steal his consciousness.
用Drain Touch掠夺他的意识
Throw him out. Pretend no one's here.
把他丢出去 当作没有人来过
Idiot.
笨蛋
(Konosuba)
美好
Isn't this Hagen?
这不是哈根吗
How come you are here?
你怎么会来这里
This is bad.
不好了
If this goes on, young lady, your only advantage will…
再这样下去 大小姐唯一的优势会…
Hey, you haven't deflated, have you?
喂 你该不会瘪掉了吧
Has her vile body deflated?
这个下流的身体瘪掉了吗
What are you talking about?
你在说什么啊
No, it's not.
不是的
If this keeps up, our family will lose its noble status,
再这样下去 我们家会被剥夺贵族资格
and the young lady's only advantage,
大小姐唯一的优势
her family status, will also disappear.
家世背景也会消失
What are you talking about?
你也是 在说什么啊
Isn't…
这个…
Isn't this the royal family's crest?
不是王家的刻印吗
What's wrong?
怎么了
No, it's nothing.
不 没什么
You have nothing to do with it.
那个 因为跟你没关系
So don't worry about it.
所以不用在意
Let me see.
让我看
I refuse.
我拒绝
Didn't you just say it?
你刚刚不是说了吗
You didn't want to get involved in trouble.
不想被扯进麻烦事里
So…
所以
Steal.
Steal
Let go.
放开
Stop.
住手
Dear great adventurer who vanquished leaders of Devil King's Army,
打倒许多魔王军干部的伟大冒险者
Kazuma Sato,
佐藤和真阁下
I would greatly appreciate the opportunity to dine with you
我想亲耳听听阁下的英勇事迹
and hear your heroic feats.
顺便与您吃顿饭
The First Princess, Eris?
第一王女 爱丽丝?
Kazuma, you should decline.
和真 婉拒吧
If something goes wrong, there will be disasters.
要是出什么差错 脑袋会不保
Besides, you don't know manners either, do you?
而且你也不懂礼仪吧
That's right.
对了
If we are going to eat,
如果要聚餐
let us just book a good restaurant…
我们就自己包下一家好吃的店
Our time has finally come.
我们的时代终于来临了啊
Kill me.
杀了我
Kill me, please.
杀了我吧
Kill me!
杀我啊
(Konosuba Season 3)
《为美好的世界献上祝福！ 第三季》
(Episode 2: A Smile for the Unsmiling Girl)
(第2集 为不笑的少女 献上微笑)
How have you been, Devil King?
您过得好吗 魔王大人
A pleasure to meet you. I am Dullahan Beldia.
幸会 我是无头骑士 贝尔迪亚
You've taken care of me in my life.
生前承蒙您照顾了…呃